<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="07">Zuko Alone</episode>
            <book n="2">Earth</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Transcript:Zuko_Alone"/>
        </head>
        
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Zuko">Zuko</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Y. Azula">Young Azula</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Ursa">Ursa</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Ozai">Dad</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Azulan">Grandpa</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Lee">Lee</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Sela">Sela</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Gow">Gow</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="OM">Old man</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="OW">Old woman</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sd>The Earth Kingdom soldiers approach him, as does their leader, Gow. Zuko dismounts and takes off his hat, placing it on the ostrich horse. They face each other, battle imminent.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	Let the kid go.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Gow">Gow</speaker>	<sd>[Laughs loudly, but quickly regains composure.]</sd> Who do you think you are, telling us what to do?</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	It doesn't matter who I am. But I know who you are. You're not soldiers; you're bullies. Freeloaders, abusing your power. Mostly over women and kids. You don't want Lee in your army – you're sick cowards messing with a family who's already lost one son to the war.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Gow">Gow</speaker>	<sd>[To a fellow soldier.]</sd> Are you gonna let this stranger stand there and insult you like this?</sp>
<sd>The soldier runs forward, spear in hand. He goes to attack Zuko, who pulls out his sword and punches the other man in the stomach with the hilt without fully unsheathing his sword. Zuko re-sheathes his sword while the man slides backward and runs away, panting heavily in fear.
A second Earth Kingdom soldier groans and runs to attack Zuko with his spear this time. Zuko punches the spear upward to move it out of the way, grabs onto the man's forehead, and shoves him to the ground. The man gets up slowly and flees as well.

A third Earth Kingdom soldier charges toward Zuko with his spear as well. Zuko stands there, waiting, until the spear is close enough and kicks the spear right in the middle, snapping it. The spearhead, along with half of the spear, goes flying in the other direction. The soldier gasps and runs away from Zuko like the two men before him. Lee laughs in satisfaction. A crowd has gathered; Sela's worried face is one of many.

With the last of his cronies gone, Gow steps up to the plate to fight Zuko, dual hammers against dual swords. They draw their weapons, and Gow throws the first blow, a rock he has earthbent, and powerfully thrusts over to Zuko. Zuko deflects it readily with his swords. Gow strikes again, this time with three large rocks instead of one. He sends them over in rapid succession to Zuko, who deflects the first two easily. However, the third rock hits him in the stomach and he stumbles backward. This does not dismay him though, so he charges Gow. An old man in the crowd cheers him on.</sd>

<sp><speaker ref="OM">Old man</speaker>	Give him a left! A left!</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="OW">Old woman</speaker>	It's not a fistfight ...</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="OM">Old man</speaker>	He's got a left sword, don't he?</sp>
<sd>Gow does the same earthbending trick as earlier; he throws three large rocks at Zuko. Zuko responds the same as before, deflecting the first two but the third one hitting him square in the abdomen. However, this time, he falls over and somersaults backward, and manages to get up, although weakened and still stumbling around. Gow smiles.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="OM">Old man</speaker>	Look out!</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Lee">Lee</speaker>	Behind you!</sp>
<sd>Gow earthbends again, but with increasingly larger rocks each time. He shoots four rocks at Zuko, who manages to destroy each, one by one. It continues this way, Gow no longer giving little recovery breaks to Zuko. Both are fighting at full force, although Zuko is so busy being defensive of the large flying rocks that he cannot become offensive to Gow. However, finally Gow creates a rockalanche and directs it at Zuko. The crowd gasps collectively. Zuko is sent flying and lands straight on his back, and has a sudden flashback.
In the flashback, Zuko is sleeping in his room at night when a hand gently touches his shoulder. He awakens drowsily to see his mother dressed in a cloak.</sd>

<sp><speaker ref="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>	... <char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>?</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Ursa">Ursa</speaker>	<char ref="Y. Zuko">Zuko</char>, please, my love, listen to me. Everything I've done, I've done to protect you.</sp>
<sd>She pulls the barely conscious Zuko into a hug.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Ursa">Ursa</speaker>	Remember this, Zuko. No matter how things may seem to change, never forget who you are.</sp>
<sd>She turns away from him with a sad smile, pulls her hood up and disappears down the dark hallway; it is the flashback Zuko had at the very beginning of the episode.
The flashback ends as suddenly as it begin, and we cut back to Zuko in the Earth Kingdom village, lying on the ground. Gow is approaching him.</sd>

<sp><speaker ref="Lee">Lee</speaker>	<sd>[Whispers worriedly.]</sd> Get up ...!</sp>
<sd>Gow raises his hammers to deliver the final blow when Zuko's eyes open. He reaches for his swords and gets up firebending, creating a hurricane of flame. Gow drops his hammers and is pushed over, and lands on his back. Zuko stands there, seething at Gow. Although unarmed, Gow stands up and raises his fists, determined to finish the fight. Zuko charges him, sending various fire blasts. Gow tries to deflect them with earthbending, but the blasts are too powerful and he is sent backward again. Rocks hit his head as he lands in with a cloud of dust.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Gow">Gow</speaker>	Who ... who are you?</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	My name is Zuko. Son of <char ref="Ursa">Ursa</char> and <char ref="Ozai">Fire Lord Ozai</char>. Prince of the Fire Nation, and heir to the throne.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="OM">Old man</speaker>	Liar! I heard of you! You're not a prince, you're an outcast! <char ref="Ozai">His own father</char> burned and disowned him!</sp>
<sd>Zuko kneels down toward Gow, who shudders in fear. However, Zuko does nothing to harm him; he only takes Lee's dagger back. Zuko walks toward Lee to give it back, but Sela (who had been untying Lee) intervenes.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Sela">Sela</speaker>	Not a step closer.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Zuko kneels down in front of Sela, with Lee peeking around his mother's back, offering the knife.]</sd> It's yours. You should have it.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Lee">Lee</speaker>	No! I hate you!</sp></scene>
            
            <scene n="2">
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>	<char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>? <sd>[Zuko leaps out of bed and runs out of his room down the hallway.]</sd> <char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>? <char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>!</sp>
<sd>Zuko enters a pillared room, where Azula is admiring Zuko's dagger from behind a pillar. She re-sheathes it and steps out to face Zuko.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>	Where's <char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>?</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Azula">Young Azula</speaker>	No one knows. Oh, and last night, <char ref="Azulan">Grandpa</char> passed away.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>	Not funny, <char ref="Y. Azula">Azula</char>! You're sick. And I want my knife back, now. <sd>[Zuko tries to grab it, but misses as Azula quickly moves out of the way, and loudly grunts.]</sd></sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Azula">Young Azula</speaker>	<sd>[Tauntingly.]</sd> Who's going to make me? <char ref="Ursa">Mom</char>?</sp>
<sd>Zuko dashes forward and grabs his knife from Azula, who was dangling in a tantalizing manner. He runs away to keep looking. Zuko reaches the garden where his father is standing still, staring into a pond.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Y. Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>	Where is she?</sp>
<sd>Ozai does not acknowledge that he has heard Zuko. Zuko bows his head.</sd></scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>