<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
            <head>
                <episode n="7">Winter Solstice Part 1: The Spirit World</episode>
                <book n="1">Water</book>
                <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Transcript:Winter_Solstice,_Part_1:_The_Spirit_World"/>
            </head>
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Zuko">Zuko</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Iroh">Iroh</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FN Soldier">Fire Nation Soldier</charList>
            <charList type="nonrecurring" id="EKCaptain">Earth Kingdon Captain</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Avatar</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sd>Back near the hot spring. Two soldiers and Zuko look for Iroh.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	<char ref="Iroh">Uncle</char>! Uncle, where are you?</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="FNSoldier">Fire Nation Soldier</speaker>	<char ref="Zuko">Sir</char>, maybe he thought you left without him.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	Something's not right here. That pile of rocks.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="FNSoldier">Fire Nation Soldier</speaker>	It looks like there's been a landslide, <char ref="Zuko">sir</char>.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	Land doesn't slide uphill. Those rocks didn't move naturally. <sd>[Stands up straight.]</sd> <char ref="Iroh">My Uncle's</char> been captured by earthbenders!</sp></scene>
            
            <scene n="2">
<sd>While following the ostrich horse footprints, Zuko notices Appa.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	The <char ref="Aang">Avatar</char>! <sd>[He turns slightly, but looks back at the footprints.]</sd></sp></scene>
            
            <scene n="3">
<sd>Back to Iroh, who is surrounded by the soldiers.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="EKCaptain">Earthbender captain</speaker>	These dangerous hands must be crushed. <sd>[He brings up and prepares to drop it. However, Zuko jumps in and kicks the rock away before breaking Iroh's chain with his boot.]</sd></sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>	Excellent form, <char ref="Zuko">Prince Zuko</char>.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	You taught me well.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="EKCaptain">Earthbender captain</speaker>	Surrender yourselves. It's five against two. You're clearly outnumbered.</sp>
<sp><speaker ref="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>	Yeah, that's true, but you are clearly outmatched.</sp>
<sd>The solders fire rocks, but Iroh destroys them with the chains. Zuko takes out two soldiers with fire. A rock is fired at him, but Iroh catches it and throws it back at the soldiers, knocking them down. The Captain fires three rocks at Zuko, which he dodges. Zuko counters with fire blasts that are dodged. The captain brings up a large mass of rock, however, Iroh throws his chains around his ankles, knocking him and causing the rocks to fall on top of him. The soldiers are heard groaning underneath the rocks.</sd>
<sp><speaker ref="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>	Now would you please put on some clothes?</sp></scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>
 
