<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<transcript>
    <head>
        <episode n="13">The Blue Spirit</episode>
        <book n="1">Water</book>
        <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Transcript:The_Blue_Spirit"/>
    </head>
    <charlist>
        
    </charlist>
    <body>
            
        <scene n="1"><sd>Cut to a Yuyan Archer, who is silent, but aims.</sd>
            <speaker ref="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>	Knock out the thief. I'll deliver him to the <char ref="Ozai">Fire Lord</char> along with the <char ref="Aang">Avatar</char>.
            <sd>The archer releases his arrow, which the camera follows across the field to its impact point on the Blue Spirit's mask. Cut to a side-view of Aang and the Blue Spirit as the masked man collapses backward in slow motion. Aang turns in horror, his eyes glazed. He recovers, turns around and airbends up a huge cloud of dust around him and the Blue Spirit.</sd>
            <speaker ref="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>	Quick! Recover the <char ref="Aang">Avatar</char>!
            <sd>Cut to the main gate opening and a crowd Fire Nation soldiers emerging and running toward the dust cloud. Cut to inside the dust cloud, where Aang removes the Blue Spirit's mask to reveal Zuko. Aang starts back in horror and falls backward on the ground. He jumps up and runs away, but turns to look at Zuko, his eyes huge and full of compassion. He sees the Fire Nation soldiers getting close through the smoke. Still, he hesitates. When the dust clears, however, the soldiers find nothing. Cut back to Zhao, looking insanely angry. A frog hops up onto the railing, croaks, and hops off.</sd></scene>

        <scene n="2"><sd>Fade to white, followed by a blurry shot of a forest looking straight up into the canopy overhead. It is morning. The screen pans down to Aang sitting on a nearby root, the view is still blurry. He looks forlorn. Cut to Zuko, whose view we were clearly just seeing. He looks a bit dazed still.</sd>
            <speaker ref="Aang">Aang</speaker>	<sd>[To Zuko.]</sd> You know what the worst part of being born over a hundred years ago is? I miss all the friends I used to hang out with. Before the war started, I used to always visit my friend Kuzon. The two of us, we'd get in and out of so much trouble together. He was one of the best friends I ever had, and he was from the Fire Nation, just like you. If we knew each other back then, do you think we could have been friends, too?
            <sd>Cut to a wide shot of Zuko lying on the ground, Aang next to him, perched a large tree root. After a pause, Zuko lets loose a huge fireball at him, but Aang dodges and flies away on a current of air. Zuko watches him hop away from tree branch to tree branch and out sight. Cut to Zuko as the camera slowly zooms backward. Zuko raises his eye in consideration.</sd></scene>
       
            </body>
        </transcript>
