<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="WarLettersSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<letter>
    <title>India- the time of my life</title>
    <abstract>This is one of many letters sent by staff of the Great Western Railway Audit office at <placeName location="Paddington"></placeName> who had enlisted to fight in the First World War.
        (RAIL 253/516)</abstract>
    <heading>
        <persName>Harry Beaumont</persName>, May 1915, <placeName location="Rawalpindi"></placeName>, <placeName location="India"></placeName>. Born: 17 October 1873, Regiment: 1/6 East Surrey Regiment, Regiment number: 2297, Rank: Quarter Master
        Sergeant, Died: 1952
        Note: Beaumont was a member of volunteer army as a young man. He was a life governor of Richmond Hospital, London and held an MBE (Military Division)
    </heading>
    
    <body>
        <p>Dear <persName>Bertie</persName>,
            Just a few lines to let you know how I am getting on. <emotion morale="high">Am having the time of my life out here</emotion>.
            No doubt you have seen the several letters I have written to the office during the past few months, so will not go into further details, except
            to say that I have been exceedingly fortunate in seeing so much of <placeName location="India"></placeName> in a short time. I shall never forget my trip through the <placeName location="Khyber Pass"></placeName>
            which has since been the scene of hard fighting, one consequence of which we were hurriedly moved from <placeName location="Fyzabad"></placeName> to <placeName location="Rawalpindi"></placeName> in readiness to
            reinforce.</p>
        
        <p><emotion morale="high">You would scarcely credit the feeling of disappointment that exists among the few British regular regiments left in India</emotion>, over not being ordered
            to <placeName location="France"></placeName> to take their share in the war. The same feeling also exists in the Territorials… A dragoon then left a few weeks ago to replace heavy
            casualties among the <placeName location="Norfolk"></placeName> regiment at the Gulf.
            As the hot weather commenced the latter part of April, and as many British troops as possible are always sent to the hills (being almost unbearable
            on the plains), we are fortunate enough to go, and had a three days’ march and climb to this place 8,000 feet up. Well I never in any wild stretch
            of imagination ever dreamed that I should be soldiering in the <placeName location="Himalayan mountains"></placeName>.
            <placeName location="Kuldana"></placeName>, although 8,000 feet up is on the lower <placeName location="Himalaya"></placeName>, and from my bungalow,which is situated on the edge of a steep precipice, I can see
            <emotion morale="high">lovely views which words fail to describe</emotion>, a perfect mixture of <placeName location="Devonshire"></placeName>, Scotch and Alpine scenery. Although seemingly only a few miles off,
            the higher snow clad ranges in full view are from 100 to 150 miles away. I have about 1½ miles trek to our Sergeant’s mess, through beautiful
            scenery, lovely wild rose bushes climbing up giant pink trees, smothering them in roses, maiden hair fern and all kinds of pretty flowers in the
            woods. <emotion morale="high">The climate is perfect, lovely English summer weather, with delightful mountain breezes. The heat in India has not distressed me in the least</emotion>,
            not even on long arduous marches. <emotion morale="high">I am feeling splendidly fit and well</emotion>, and trust I shall continue so. We have no end of gaiety; all the married
            families of the <placeName location="Yorkshire"></placeName> regiment are living in our barracks under our charge, (as their regiments had to remain behind at <placeName location="Pindi"></placeName>, and are being
            bitten to death almost with mosquitoes.) So we have Cinderella dances about three times a week, whist drives, racquet and tennis parties and <emotion morale="high">have
                most enjoyable times</emotion>.</p>
        
        <p>I wish <persName>May</persName> and <persName>Eileen</persName> could take an aeroplane trip of a few hours and get to me, it would be ripping for them. I should be glad to hear that you
            had called to see them on your promised visit of months ago when I was home, they would be awfully glad to see you both. Do drop them a card old
            boy. Fancy it is 10 months ago today since I left to go to camp, what a lot has transpired since then. I was in the 8th Middlesex 12 months ago,
            and I see they have lost heavily in <placeName location="France"></placeName>, funny I should have left them, and joined the 6th East Surrey and to pass them at <placeName location="Gibraltar"></placeName>
            (where they were first) on my way to <placeName location="India"></placeName>.</p>
    </body>
    
    <closing><emotion morale="high">On the whole I am enjoying life in India immensely</emotion>; I am acting Company Sergeant Major now, and expect to be promoted to the rank shortly.
        We are all ‘Tommies’ now. Trusting you are both fit and well. Remember me to <persName>Stacey</persName>. Yours sincerely,
        <persName>H. Beaumont</persName></closing>
</letter>